Excuse me, ma'am.
Thanks, wait. 502.
Question for you.
Um...
I will take care of that.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
Is this your Ferrari?
Yes, it is.
And what do you do
for living out here in Scottsdale
to be able to afford a Ferrari?
I'm an entrepreneur.
How long have you been a business owner for?
Three years.
Three years?
Yeah.
What was the most amount of money
that you've ever made in a single year?
So the most amount of money
that we have done will be this year.
We'll do about $250 million.
About $100 million.
North of $20 million annual reoccurring revenue.
Have you ever been broke before?
Yeah, dude, I was in the military for 22 years.
Yeah?
Of course I was broke.
And what did you do after the military?
I started buying and selling businesses.
What was the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
11 mil.
How old are you?
Just turned 60.
You're not 60 years old.
Yeah, 23rd of July, I turned 60.
What's the secret to looking
like this at 60 years old?
That's crazy.
Focus, man.
Everything's about focus and discipline.
How can somebody become a multimillionaire in 2024
like yourself?
Hard Knocks family,
we just got to our destination at Fashion Square
in Scottsdale, Arizona.
One of the richest cities in the entire country.
And I'm going to be
going all over to find multimillionaires
up to people who've built billion dollar companies
to figure out how they became wealthy
and the secret to becoming financially free in 2024.
So with that being said, let's go get these interviews.
Question for you.
Have you ever been broke before?
No.
And what do you do
for living out here in Scottsdale?
I'm done.
Quick question for you.
Have you ever been broke before?
Have I ever been what?
Fuck yeah.
Yeah?
Hasn't everybody?
Yeah.
What do you do for living out here in Scottsdale?
I don't.
I'm just visiting right now.
What industry?
I don't really like social media.
Real quick, real quick.
No, no.
I have a channel.
I started at UT Austin.
I grew up to 6 million followers.
You what?
I started a channel at UT Austin.
I grew up to 6 million followers.
I interview business.
You're great, man.
Thank you, bro.
Excuse me, sir.
Question for you, sir.
Question for you.
Have you ever owned a business before?
Yes.
Yeah?
What type of company?
Archie Guys.
So as you guys can see, since we
are in the wealthiest city in all of Arizona,
it is very hard to get access
to these people to do an interview with.
And these people understand the value of their time,
and they are always on the go out here,
man.
So we're going to do everything we can
to get the best content possible for you guys.
So stay tuned because I'm not leaving this
video until I deliver you guys a million dollars
worth of game.
Let's go get these interviews.
Come on.
Excuse me, sir.
Question for you.
How old were you when you became a millionaire?
Yup.
And how old are you now?
And what do you do
for living out here in Scottsdale?
I own a healthcare company
and a couple of software companies.
And how long have you been an entrepreneur for?
Well, I guess my whole career, 24 years.
And what was the lowest point
in your career as an entrepreneur?
Probably like 10 years ago.
I gambled on the wrong staff and
they burned me and picked myself back up.
And there's nobody you can reinvest into besides yourself.
What was your superpower as a business owner?
I just talked to everybody on a regular basis.
Communication.
Communication, for sure.
So I'm assuming you're a salesperson then?
Nope.
I'm a retired doctor.
Retired doctor?
Yeah.
Well, I own the company now,
but I'm the founder and CEO.
Okay.
So I guess in terms of revenue across
all these businesses, what has been the most amount
of money that you've ever made in a single year?
About a hundred million.
A hundred million dollars?
And what are you selling?
We're in healthcare.
So we provide primary care for trauma patients.
Right.
So we do everything.
We do all the surgeries.
We do scar revisions.
We do site counseling.
We do PT.
We do chiro.
We do just general medical management.
Everything.
Do you come from money?
No, not at all.
McDonald's was a cool thing as a kid.
That was like a real treat and reward.
How did you change your family's trajectory?
What did you see that made you
want to get really serious about becoming financially
free and really successful in business?
My dad built custom homes as a hobby.
And he always pointed out everybody
in the neighborhood didn't have a job.
They owned something.
So I think I took that insight as, well, when
I become a doctor, I'm going to own my practice
and then kind of become a doctor.
So it kind of expanded from there.
How did you get the money to start your business?
Did you have to borrow
any money or leverage any capital?
Nope.
I'm the only owner.
No other banks.
No other personal or private equity.
Nothing.
It's just me.
So you built a $100 million company.
Same, same, same.
Well, it's worth maybe a billion
now, but it's, yeah, we do well.
What is your net worth?
It's somewhere between $500 and $700 million and maybe more.
So what did you have to
sacrifice to build a $100 million company?
I never saw my kids wake up.
I never saw them go to bed.
I work six days a week.
I took Sundays off to take a nap.
My wife over here said that everybody
said, did you hire him for Facebook?
Because we've never met your husband
because all he does is work.
So I think I sacrificed a lot of my
children's youth, but now they're teenagers and I'm there
every day.
So it's cool.
And are you guys married?
Yes.
Let me ask you a question.
What's the number one thing that you're
the most proud of about your husband?
Everything.
Yeah.
He's an amazing husband.
I mean, he's worked harder
than everybody that I've ever seen.
Thank you so much, Fred.
I appreciate that, man.
Yeah, absolutely.
Hard Knocks family.
We just ran into a
$100 million a year entrepreneur out.
Yeah.
Here whose net worth is
in between five and $700 million.
He's in the business of healthcare, but what did
he say is one of the most important financial
decisions that you can make is keeping
all the money back into the business.
He didn't have any investors.
He didn't go into any debt.
So he owns that entire business and he
kept the money back into the business because if
you have one bad month as a business owner
and you blow your cash, it's all gone and
you could be done.
So great interview out here.
Let's go get this next one.
Keep this video rolling.
Come on.
All right, you guys, we got somebody pull
up on a Ferrari right at the Valley right
here.
We're going to go up and see what they were
able to do to be able to afford this car.
Let's go see what they have to say.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Thanks.
Question for you.
Um, we'll take care of that.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Is this your Ferrari?
Yes it is.
And what do you do for living out here
in Scottsdale to be able to afford a Ferrari?
I'm an entrepreneur.
How long have you been a business owner for?
Three years.
Yes.
I go all over the country just asking
business owners their best advice to new entrepreneurs.
Could I ask you a couple
of quick questions for the channel?
Sure.
Awesome.
So what are you doing right now in entrepreneurship?
I own an online fitness and nutrition company.
And you've been in that business the last three years?
Three years.
And what's the most amount of money
that you've ever made in a single year?
So the most amount of money that
we have done will be this year.
We'll do north of $20 million annual reoccurring revenue.
$20 million.
And that's just the start, by the way, okay?
Because we're going to scale
this thing to over $100 million.
That's incredible.
I know we can do it.
Let me first ask you this.
How did you scale this
company from seven to eight figures?
A lot of business owners, they have a great idea.
They start, they really struggle to scale.
You specialize in scaling companies.
What took your company from seven to eight figures?
First of all, you got
to dial in capturing the demand.
So marketing and sales is huge.
If you don't have somebody overseeing and
driving the function of marketing and sales,
you don't have a business, right?
But then the challenges then that you face
as a business owner is not just capturing
the demand and then converting it, but
fulfilling the service so that the client experience
doesn't break.
So that requires somebody who has a lot
of operational experience to come in and build
systems and process.
Now, as a multiple eight figure entrepreneur,
what was the best financial advice that you
ever received?
You have to bet on yourself.
You can't focus on what you're making.
Now.
So there was a time that
only made $19,000 a year, right?
But here mentally, I was always rich, you know?
So it's a mindset.
You have to take the money that
you're making and continuously reinvest in yourself.
And you have to keep
doing that all the way through.
That's how you're going to earn more money over time.
So you're the best bet that you can make.
A lot of people value money over valuing themselves.
I value myself over money,
which is why I'm so rich.
How old are you now?
How old were you when you became a millionaire?
I was actually 40.
40 years old.
That took me a long time, right?
So it's never too late, right?
Age is just a number.
It's all about how you feel
and that energy that you have inside.
But if you were to go back in time
and have a conversation with your 20 year old self,
when you were starting from zero, what's the
best advice that you would give to your younger
self?
To not give a fuck what anybody thinks about you.
You have to believe in yourself.
I think when I was younger, I didn't
have relentless belief in myself and I wasn't unapologetic
about who I was.
It took me a long time
to be who I am today.
You got amazing advice.
Thank you so much.
Thank you for your time.
Thank you.
I appreciate it.
Hard Knocks family, this video has been crazy so far.
We're on our way to go get our next
interview right now, but I've got a very special announcement
to make.
A couple of weeks ago, we launched
our official entrepreneur community, the School of Mentors.
We've already hit a thousand members and for
the people that have joined, they can hop
on live calls every single week to learn
from, connect with, and get directly mentored by
the multi-millionaires and the billionaires
that I interview on this channel.
They can ask some questions about
their career, their life, and their business.
So you do not want to miss out on this
opportunity because it's once in a lifetime to be able
to get this access to the
people I interview on this channel.
Every single week.
So to join now, click the link
down in the description of this video below.
We'll see you on the inside, but with
that being said, let's go get this next interview.
Come on.
Excuse me, sir.
Question for you.
Sure.
Have you ever owned a business before?
Yes.
Probably a dozen or two.
Yeah?
And what industry did you
decide to pursue a career in?
I've been in a bunch of industries, electronics, logistics.
What was your main company?
What was my...
Nobody you've ever heard of.
Yeah?
Just small business.
I started the channel at the University of Texas.
I started the channel...
Oh, you're an Austin boy, huh?
Yes, sir.
I grew the channel to over six million.
I have over six million followers.
I go all over the country just
asking business owners a couple of quick questions.
Can I get just one minute of your time?
Look, I'm trying to get my daughter in a wheelchair.
For sure.
How long have you been an entrepreneur for?
40 years.
And do you come from a lot of money?
No.
What did your parents do?
Small business owner.
I worked in my father's business through high
school and college, and then he and I started
a business in the early 80s out of that.
What company did you start?
We started...
It's in the electronics industry.
It's a small little distributorship in industrial selling.
Yeah.
Pretty much been my whole career.
So in terms of revenue, what was the most
amount of money that you ever made in a single
year?
We did revenue about 250 million in the good years.
$250 million.
What's more important, product or distribution?
It's A or B. And neither one, actually.
Products can be okay.
Distribution's just a channel, but it's
all about how you implement your plan.
There's a lot of great products and a lot
of good plans, but you got to implement it
right.
How did you scale from an
eight to a nine figure business?
There's a guy who wrote a book, Collins,
I believe his name is, Get the Right People
on the Bus.
And it starts with the right people, and
then it's about the business plan, financing it,
and good partners.
What was your relationship with debt as a business owner?
Did you have to borrow money
from banks to start and grow businesses?
Or how did you-
Yes.
Yeah?
But it's very hard because unless you
have money, they don't loan you money.
So trying to get started, it's one of
the biggest problems we have today is banks don't
loan money to small businesses.
So getting started is very hard.
I actually fund some stuff with small
businesses today, and it's very, very difficult because,
private equity and strategics have rolled up
every industry, and banks only give money
to the insiders.
And you've sold hundreds of millions
of dollars in revenue throughout your career.
What was your secret to sales?
The issue in terms of selling is there's
some sellers that are, we call them hunters, and
there's some sales guys that are farmers.
Do you know what those are?
You ever heard those phrases?
I haven't heard that before.
So a hunter is somebody who goes
to look for new companies, new business.
A farmer is somebody who gets
more business out of the existing customers.
So manager business, it's a combination of both.
You got it?
I got to go grab a thing.
I appreciate you.
How old are you now?
You look incredible for 62.
And real quick, I'm 22.
Whose generation works harder, yours or mine?
Well, individuals in your generation do well, but
as a whole, one of the problems we have
is, good expression for you, it's in
the old days, it's always, I earn.
Today it's, I deserve, not I earn.
So entitlement's a big problem you see.
Huge problem, which isn't necessarily the kid's problem.
It's the parents for providing it.
So the whole thing is everybody gets a trophy.
I was a chairman.
Yeah.
I was a chairman of a regional
board of education I got voted into.
And I sat there at the negotiation and I said,
okay, teachers, what we want to do is we have
a bunch of middle schools I want to
start comparing teachers of English class and blah,
blah, blah.
Well, we don't do that.
I said, well, wait a minute.
Do you teach your kids that A's
are better than B's or better than C's?
Yeah, but not for us.
Yeah.
It's part of what we're dealing with right now.
Thank you.
Take care guys.
Have a great day.
Good luck.
Bye-bye.
Take care.
Yeah, thats me.
Bye-bye.
My real favorite part this morning and
I'm football you really wanna talk about
is that, um, I go
out and manage that kids grandpa.
Yeah.
He told me he makes 10, 10 million
dollars as if I'm fucking working for you.
Ok.
So it's like, it's part of what I do so
I can share like a buddy that I'm like being
fun, kind of freaking with you just
to make sure that you understand the basics.
Right.
Your life, it's just so terrible for us kids.
You mean what you mean what sick for you?
Yeah.
Cool.
I was broke. And what did you do
after the military? I started buying and selling businesses,
moved overseas. Yeah? Yeah. So I ran aviation
in Africa, construction in South America. Wow. So
you were in like private equity, venture capital. What
are you doing right now? Oh yeah, yeah. Some
VC, some private equity, investment banking. Eight out
of 10 businesses, they won't make it past five
years. What's the most common mistake that you
see business owners make that prevents them? Cash flow.
Cash flow. Cash flow. It's really simple. What is
the secret to managing that cash flow and turning
it into real wealth? Having an 18 month cash
flow model and then making sure that you're staying,
keeping your head above water. Revenue is awesome, but
you got to have cash flow to keep the doors
open. In terms of revenue though, across all your
companies, what was the most amount of money that
you ever made in a single year? 11 mil. 11
million dollars. And how did you scale from seven to eight
figures? And what was your secret to
scaling businesses? Focus. Yeah. No, no life balance,
no family, no kids, no girlfriends, just business.
What was the best financial advice that you ever
received? Don't lose it. Break
that down. How can you? No,
make good deals, man. Yeah. Yeah. Nothing is
real until you have a contract. Always have a
contract. Always make sure that you're, you're
keeping your hands above table. You do everything
transparently. You don't do anything illegal, immoral
or unethical. You've been at the table
with some heavy hitters, I'm sure. Yeah. What
is your best negotiation advice for people out there?
Don't talk past the sale. Once you've got the
sale done, don't keep talking. Keep your mouth shut.
Just keep your mouth shut. Yeah. But what was
your secret to sales and generating millions of dollars
in revenue over these years? I'm not the sales guy.
That's my secret is I know my, I know my
strengths and I know my weaknesses. So what
was your superpower then as a business owner? Motivation.
Leadership. Leadership. Yeah. Taking, taking my
special operations background and being able to
apply it to apply it to business. So you
were special ops in the military? Yes, sir. What branch?
Army. Were you a ranger? Army, Green
Beret. That's incredible, sir. How important was that
military background in the business? Invaluable. Yeah.
I wouldn't have changed it for anything.
What was the lowest point in your career? Losing
friends. How did you overcome that? And let's say
somebody going through a tough time right now in
life. How did you kind of overcome the adversity
that you face in your life and business
and the military? Daily gratitude. Yeah. I've got mantras
in the morning that I go through.
Meditation. Just staying positive, man. And make you
so much for your time. Thanks guys. Appreciate you, man.
Remind me your name? Jeff. Jeff, how old are you?
Just turned 60. You're not 60 years old. Yeah.
23rd of July, I turned 60, man. Are you serious?
Yeah. What's the secret to looking like this
at 60 years old, man? That's crazy. Focus, man.
Everything's about focus and discipline. You're 60 today.
If you were to go back 40 years ago,
what advice would you give to your 20 year
old self to have that same blueprint of romantic
success? Stay in the fight. Stay in the fight.
Stay in the fight, man. Yes, sir. Thank you,
my friend. You got amazing advice. Be
good, man. Have a good day. Thank you.
Hard Knocks family. That's a wrap on
today's video. Scottsdale was absolutely amazing. Again,
but I want you to like and subscribe for
amazing content we've got coming very, very soon. And as
I mentioned earlier, our private entrepreneur
community hit over 1000 members because the
people that join can connect with, learn
directly from, and get mentored by the multi-millionaires
and the billionaires I interview on this channel every
single week. You do not want to miss out on
this opportunity to join. So click the link down
in the description or click right here and I'll
see you on the inside. But with that
being said, we'll see you in the next video.